

Profile

I'm a pragmatic Software Engineer living at the intersection of design, code, and UX. I believe in crafting maintainable, scalable and performant products that delight users and satisfy the unique needs of your business. I specialize full-stack JavaScript development and the mobile web.

Experience

Software Engineer @ Squarespace

12/2018 - Present • New York, NY • squarespace.com

Member of the Trial Experience team at Squarespace. Responsible for measurably improving product conversion rate by reducing friction points during user onboarding. Primarily worked in TypeScript, React & Redux.

Frontend Engineer @ Reserve Media

06/2017 - Present • New York, NY • reserve.com

Built the frontend for all Reserve web products. Rebuilt consumer platform with focus on mobile performance resulting in a 6x improvement to page load speed, drastically improved browser compatibility & heightened reservation rates.

Mobile Web Team Lead @ Forbes Magazine

04/2015 - 06/2017 • Jersey City, NJ • forbes.com

Shipped improvements to Forbes.com, enhancing the web experience for 10 million monthly users. Lead dev on new mobile-optimized article experience resulting in 3x increase in engagement & 50% increase in time on page.

Web Applications Developer @ Rochester Institute of Technology

08/2013 - 01/2015 • Rochester, NY • rit.edu/asc/online

Single student developer overseeing the rebranding, maintenance & expansion of dozens of web apps under the Student Academic Support Center. Collaborated with Students and Faculty to create ad-hoc solutions to meet department needs.

Fullstack Developer Internship @ Magnani Caruso Dutton

06/2014 - 08/2014 • New York, NY • mcdpartners.com

Solely developed front and back end of an internal expense reporting platform used by MCD employees. Developed single page promotional experiences for clients including Samsung, Discover Financial, and HBO.

Web Developer Internship @ Datto, Inc.

08/2012 - 11/2012 • Norwalk, CT • datto.com

Assisted in the redevelopment of all Datto Backup client-facing portals - account management, subscription services, etc. Focused on the creation of a consistent, responsive component library to be deployed across all web products.

Education

B.Sc, New Media Interactive Development

2010 - 2014 • Rochester, New York • 3.55 GPA

College of Computing and Information Sciences Rochester Institute of Technology

Contact

tom@thomasconroy.net https://conroy.codes

Languages

- Modern JavaScript (ES6+)
- NodeJS
- TypeScript
- HTML5
- CSS3
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- GraphQL (Relay, Apollo)

Client-Side

- React
- Preact
- AngularJS
- Vue.js
- Express
- React Native
- Redux
- ImmutableJS
- ServiceWorkers
- Styled Components

Server-Side

- Express
- Koa
- Hapi
- Laravel
- SailsIS
- LoopBack
- Sequelize

Tooling

- SCM / Git
- Unix, Bash / ZSH Shells
- Webpack, Gulp, Parcel
- SASS, css-modules
- Virtualization (i.e Docker)
- Sketch, Figma, Adobe CS
- Amazon Web Services

Methodologies

- Agile, Scrum
- Test-Driven Development
- RESTful API design
- mobile-first development

Social



y t_conroy



tconroy tconroy

